aami.com.au 2005-12-23

# AAMI - Security and Privacy Policy

Print page

1\. About this Security and Privacy Statement

This website is owned and operated by or on behalf of Australian Associated Motor Insurers Limited ABN 92 004 791 744 (“AAMI”) and includes all web pages under the domain name “aami.com.au” and any other AAMI-branded web pages which include an authorised link to this Security and Privacy Statement (the “AAMI Website”).

This Security and Privacy Statement explains our policy for handling personal information which you may provide to us as you access and interact with the AAMI Website. This Statement should be read in conjunction with:

  * our brochure “[AAMI and Your Personal Information](http://www.aami.com.au/products/policy/privacy/pdf/AAMI_4109_Privacy_Brochure.pdf)”, which deals with our handling of personal information generally; and
  * the AAMI [Website Terms of Use.](http://www.aami.com.au/privacy_terms/terms.asp)

As the AAMI Website develops and as technology evolves, AAMI will continue to strive to provide you with better services. AAMI encourages you to review the AAMI Security and Privacy Statement periodically as it may be updated from time to time.

In addition to the provisions of this Security and Privacy Statement, there may also be specific and additional privacy provisions which apply to certain parts of the AAMI Website. You should review such additional provisions where applicable and accessible via the AAMI Website.

2\. Your Security and Privacy

AAMI understands and appreciates that you, as an AAMI Website visitor, are concerned about your security, privacy and the confidentiality of information we may gain about you online. We at AAMI have always prided ourselves on playing a proactive role in the development of quality, best practice privacy policies for both our customer base and for individuals who provide us with information in relation to employment with AAMI.

Since the introduction of the AAMI Customer Charter in 1996, a group of its key promises have dealt with the privacy, access to, and right of correction of, customers' personal information. (For full details, go to: [AAMI Customer Charter](http://www.aami.com.au/aami_customer_service/customer_charter.asp)). AAMI’s induction and ongoing employee programs, such as Charter Training encompass training in privacy policies and procedures. Every effort is made to ensure that our employees are aware of our policies regarding privacy.

Two of the four personal information promises in the current Charter are that:

  * We value the personal information you give us and will take all reasonable precautions to prevent unauthorised access to that information.
  * We will not give your personal information to any other organisation for their marketing purposes.

Whilst these promises apply to the AAMI Website with the same force as they do to all other AAMI activities, we have taken specific measures to respect your privacy and the security of any personal information you may provide to us while visiting the AAMI Website.

3\. Emailing AAMI

Unless otherwise stated, when you send us an email, the contents of your email and your email address is retained by AAMI for only as long as it takes to respond to your inquiry unless you provide us with your permission to retain that information or where we believe there is a legal reason to retain the information for a longer period.

4\. Information collected and how we use it

**4.1 General information**

> The information which we will collect about you will depend on how you use the AAMI Website.
> 
> If you visit the AAMI Website to read, browse or download information, our computer system will record information such as the date and time of your visit to the AAMI Website, the pages accessed and any information downloaded. This information is used for statistical, reporting and website administration and maintenance purposes only.
> 
> The AAMI Website also uses the services of Red Sheriff to monitor website use. Red Sheriff does not collect any personal information while you use the AAMI Website and the reports it provides to AAMI are of aggregated information only. These reports help AAMI to maintain, administer and improve the AAMI Website.
> 
> The AAMI Website may offer interactive facilities including premium calculators and online application forms. If you use any interactive features, we may capture any personal information which you may enter when using these tools.
> 
> The AAMI Website may offer competitions or promotions, for example the AAMI Lucky promotion. When you submit an entry in such a competition, AAMI will print out your application form and record contact details in our mainframe system. AAMI may use this information to contact you at a future time. This information is purged from our mainframe system on a regular basis.
> 
> Where practical we collect your personal information directly from you. We may collect personal information about you when you deal with us by telephone, letter, email, or visit the AAMI Website.

**4.2 Obtaining an insurance quote**

> All personal information you provide to AAMI over the Internet while inquiring about or obtaining an insurance quotation is passed through a secure, encrypted connection. The secure connection is over a protocol called secure sockets layer (SSL). AAMI uses 128-bit SSL encryption, which provides one of the highest levels of protection against unauthorised access in order to prevent unauthorised persons from reading the information you send to AAMI while it is in transit over the Internet.
> 
> Once your personal information and any payment details have been received at the AAMI website, we take all reasonable precautions to securely pass that information to the AAMI mainframe computer. The AAMI mainframe computer is not directly accessible through the Internet, and several levels of firewall security are employed to prevent illegitimate access to our mainframe. No details you provide to us are stored on a web server.
> 
> If you have not proceeded with your AAMI on-line quotation within 30 days of its issue, it is automatically and completely removed from our records. Within this period, your details are never stored on any web server or computer system directly connected to the Internet. 

**4.3 AAMI recruitment**

> As part of our recruitment process, we will gather information on your background, including personal information that you include on your application or resume, such as your name, mailing address, telephone number, email address, career history, details of any competency tests or other information relating to your career.
> 
> In some circumstances, we may also collect sensitive information about you such as information about your membership of a professional or trade association or trade union; security clearance or any criminal record(s) or charges you may have had filed against you. When we need to collect this type of information, we will obtain your consent.
> 
> There may be occasions when we obtain personal information about you from a third party; for example, when receiving the results of a psychological or competency test or assessment centre results. When we need to collect this type of information, we will obtain your consent prior to you taking part in the exercise.
> 
> In relation to the collection of personal information regarding references, we will not approach any referees without your specific permission or knowledge.
> 
> Please be aware, if you do not provide AAMI with the information we require, we may be limited in our ability to consider you for employment.
> 
> We will only use your personal information collected in relation to recruitment for the primary purpose of employment with AAMI.
> 
> Should AAMI engage/employ third party contractors or vendors to perform recruitment services for us, which involves handling your personal information we will take reasonable steps to prohibit these parties from using your personal information except for the purposes for which it was supplied.
> 
> In instances where AAMI engages a third party recruitment agency to assist with our recruitment efforts, we will ensure that their privacy policy commitments compliment ours.

**4.4 Third party sites**

> The AAMI Website may contain links to websites which are owned or operated by third parties independent of AAMI (“Third Party Websites”). Third Party Websites should contain their own privacy statements and, should you choose to access those Third Party Websites, they are responsible for informing you about their security and privacy practices.

5\. Making an online payment to AAMI

When you make a payment on our Website using your credit card, your credit card number is passed in a secure manner between the AAMI Website and third party payment providers, such as the issuer of your credit card. Your credit card number will be recorded in the AAMI mainframe computer system, and will not be transmitted over the Internet to credit card providers or payment providers. AAMI, and any payment providers will not store your credit card details on any web server. If your credit card number is stored, it will be only for AAMI or bank record keeping purposes, and then it will be stored with an even higher level of encryption.

6\. Cookies

The AAMI Website uses “cookies” as a fundamental part of its interaction with your Internet browser. Cookies enable AAMI to provide you with a superior and more customised service.

A “cookie” is a small text file placed on your computer by our web server. A cookie can later be retrieved by the AAMI Website servers. Cookies are frequently used on websites and you can choose if and how a cookie will be accepted by configuring your preferences and options in your browser. Cookies do not alter the operation of your computer in any way.

Cookies are used by the AAMI Website to enable the AAMI Website online insurance quotation and purchase processes. Most of the AAMI Website operates by use of cookies. Therefore, if you wish to make full use of the AAMI Website, it is recommended that you accept cookies. Cookies may also be used to record non-personalised information such as the date, time or duration of your visit, or the pages accessed, for website administration, statistical and maintenance purposes. Any such information will be aggregated and not attributed to individual users.

7\. Use and disclosure of information

We collect personal information for the purposes of communicating with our customers, setting premiums appropriately, investigating and paying claims, providing products and services that meet our customers’ needs and compiling statistics. We may also use or disclose personal information we collect in relation to the AAMI Website or visitors to the AAMI Website:

  * in accordance with this Security and Privacy Statement;
  * where you have consented to the use or disclosure;
  * for purposes related to AAMI’s research (including market research), planning, service development, security, testing and risk management (Note: we will not disclose your personal information to external market research companies without further basis under this Security and Privacy Statement, e.g. your consent);
  * for purposes connected with the operation, administration, development or enhancement of the AAMI Website;
  * where a third party acquires, or considers acquiring, an interest in AAMI;
  * where AAMI is authorised, required or permitted by law to use or disclose the information.

We may provide personal information we collect through the AAMI Website to third parties. The types of third parties to whom we would usually disclose that personal information may include:

  * our service providers who assist us in providing the AAMI Website and our products and services (for example internet and technology service providers, mail houses, call centres, credit card and payment providers, and delivery companies); or
  * insurance reference service providers.

8\. Access

If you have any queries about privacy, or if you wish to request access to any personal information which we hold about you please contact:

**Ebusiness Operations Manager  
AAMI ebusiness  
601 St Kilda Rd Melbourne 3004  
Phone: 13 22 44  

Prior to releasing this information, AAMI may require a written request or proof of identity.

We respect your rights to review this information, and we will endeavour to provide information within a reasonable time, however, we are entitled to charge you a reasonable fee for access to this information.

For information about how to obtain copies of documents such as policy information and claims documents, please see our brochure “[AAMI and Your Personal Information](http://www.aami.com.au/products/policy/privacy/pdf/AAMI_4109_Privacy_Brochure.pdf)”.

9\. Acceptance and changes to Security and Privacy Statement

You acknowledge and accept that your use of the AAMI Website indicates your acceptance of the AAMI Website Terms of Use and the Security and Privacy Statement.

This is the current Security and Privacy Statement. It replaces any other Security and Privacy Statement for the AAMI Website published on the AAMI Website to date. AAMI may at any time vary the Security and Privacy Statement by publishing the varied Security and Privacy Statement on the AAMI Website.

AAMI is under no obligation to specifically notify you of any variation to the Security and Privacy Statement. You accept that by your use of the AAMI Website after any variation, AAMI has provided you with sufficient notice of the variation and you are taken to have accepted the new Security and Privacy Statement.

(C) Copyright 2000 Australian Associated Motor Insurers Limited  
ABN 92 004 791 744 Version 2 - 21 December 2004

  ABN 92 004 791 744      AFSL 238173 |  |     
---|---|---
